<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://tanyuanxiangelroy.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://tanyuanxiangelroy.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-03-31T09:55:11+00:00</updated><id>https://tanyuanxiangelroy.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Get started with this 3D printing resources</title><link href="https://tanyuanxiangelroy.github.io/blog/2024/3D-printing-resorces/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Get started with this 3D printing resources"/><published>2024-03-25T15:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-03-25T15:59:00+00:00</updated><id>https://tanyuanxiangelroy.github.io/blog/2024/3D-printing-resorces</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://tanyuanxiangelroy.github.io/blog/2024/3D-printing-resorces/"><![CDATA[<p>This is a curated list of resources I use. Hopefully, this is a pool of resources can jump-start your learning.</p> <p>I have been 3D printing since 2020 and own a 3D printer since 2021. The resources may not be the most up-to-date but they are what work for me. I will update this when I find something useful.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="website-for-stl">Website for STL</h2> <p>If you don’t want to design their own models or lack the skill or time, the Internet allows people can share their models, and you can benefit by downloading and using their files.</p> <blockquote class="block-warning"> <h5 id="warning">WARNING</h5> <p>A good rule of thumb is not to download g-code from websites as the code may be malicious or wrongly configured and damage your printer. Always download the file and slice it yourself or let the owner of the printer slice the model into g-code, as they should know their printer the best.</p> </blockquote> <blockquote class="block-tip"> <h5 id="ps">p.s.</h5> <p>Most models are posted on multiple websites, but it is good to check them all. You might be able to find additional models as there are websites that specialize in certain areas.</p> </blockquote> <h3 id="thingiverse"><a href="https://www.thingiverse.com/">Thingiverse</a></h3> <p>The OG STL website is one that most people in the 3D printing space know about. However, I don’t use it anymore as I dislike the UI and there are better websites out there.</p> <p>Side note: I just went back to it, and the quality of the stl and demo picture really improved a lot.</p> <h3 id="printables"><a href="https://www.printables.com/">Printables</a></h3> <p>This is my primary STL website for 3D printing. The content is better than Thingiverse, as there are periodic competitions in selected themes, and there is honestly more stuff here.</p> <p>There is a reward mechanism that I have seen people use to get free, high-quality filament from Prusa.</p> <h3 id="maker-world"><a href="https://makerworld.com/en">Maker World</a></h3> <p>The newest website of the batch that I am using is honestly looking very promising.With them also doing periodic competitions in selected themes and inviting people to create models specially for their website.</p> <p>There are YouTubers who redeemed a Bambu 3D printer with this website.</p> <hr/> <p>These are good mentions. However, I don’t use them often, as they are paid websites.</p> <h3 id="cults3d"><a href="https://cults3d.com/en">Cults3d</a></h3> <p>It has high-quality models that are unique to the website. But it is because they are paid models.</p> <p>If you are opening a store and need some models to print, I recommend looking at this website. It offers legal ways get models that you can print and sell.</p> <h3 id="my-mini-factory"><a href="https://www.myminifactory.com/">My Mini Factory</a></h3> <p>They have unique models for miniatures, but they are mostly paid.</p> <p>Sometimes you can get them for free. If you play D&amp;D or anything that requires miniatures, this is a good place to go.</p> <hr/> <p>These are more general model websites I use and not specifically for 3D printing.</p> <p>This means most of the models were not designed with 3D printing and would need a lot of supports when printed.</p> <h3 id="grabcad"><a href="https://grabcad.com/library">GrabCAD</a></h3> <p>It is more of a mechanical model website. I use it to get accurate models of mechanical parts that I use, like nuts and bolts.</p> <h3 id="thangs"><a href="https://thangs.com/">Thangs</a></h3> <p>It’s more like a library of models. I like it because it is free to use, and there are nice models of TV and movie characters like Pokémon.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="cad-software">CAD software</h2> <p>Now you want to take it up a notch and start customizing your own models to print. CAD (computer-aided design)software allows you to design models in 3D.</p> <h3 id="thinkercad"><a href="https://www.tinkercad.com/">ThinkerCAD</a></h3> <p>If you have participated in any basic 3D printing workshop, they will recommend this as it is very basic, simple, and web-based. Thus, you just need an internet connection to get started. </p> <p>You drag and drop blocks to create the shape you want, making it easy to learn and teach. But for more complicated designs and objects, it is tedious to make them in ThinkerCAD.</p> <h3 id="onshape"><a href="https://www.onshape.com/en/sign-up">Onshape</a></h3> <p>I recommend this CAD software for anyone starting out.</p> <p>You just need an internet connection to get started. Because it has a free version and is web-based. There is a learning curve, but it will teach you the proper way of cadding and allow you to design more intricate designs.</p> <h3 id="fusion360"><a href="https://www.autodesk.com/products/fusion-360/personal">Fusion360</a></h3> <p>It is the CAD software I primarily use.</p> <p>The only reason I use it is because it is free for students and my School needs it. I have never tried it’s free personal use license, so I can’t recommend it.</p> <blockquote class="block-tip"> <p>No matter which CAD software you choose try not to skip around too much as each has it own separate shortcut and controls that you need time to get used to</p> </blockquote> <h2 id="slicers-software">Slicers software</h2> <p>Now, you need to convert your models into G-Code readable files for your printer to print.</p> <h3 id="curaslicer"><a href="https://ultimaker.com/software/ultimaker-cura/">CuraSlicer</a></h3> <p>The one I used the longest and is the most basic, but with plug-ins, you can get it to do a lot of things.</p> <h3 id="prusaslicer"><a href="https://www.prusa3d.com/en/page/prusaslicer_424/">PrusaSlicer</a></h3> <p>It’s great if you have a pusa machine and its accompanying filament. It’s a good slicer that I used for a while since the school club used this as well.</p> <h3 id="bambu--studio"><a href="https://bambulab.com/en/download/studio">Bambu Studio</a></h3> <p>The latest slicer I used and the one I am currently using the reason is that I can share the account I make for it with trusted people and my preset and configurations will sink up.</p> <blockquote class="block-tip"> <p>No matter which slicer software you choose, try not to skip around too much, As you should fine tune the profile of your printer in each slicer. Due to each slicer converting and optimizing the g-code differently.</p> </blockquote> <hr/> <h2 id="other-resources-that-i-rely-on">Other resources that I rely on</h2> <h3 id="blog">Blog</h3> <ul> <li><a href="https://all3dp.com/">all3dp</a></li> </ul> <p>I use this blog when I just want something to print without thinking. I look at their catalog of models for specific usage. Plus, they explain the basics of 3D printing quite well.</p> <h3 id="youtube-creators">Youtube creators</h3> <ul> <li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/@MakersMuse">Makers Muse</a></li> <li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/@CNCKitchen">CNC Kitchen</a></li> <li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/@thenextlayer">The Next Layer</a></li> <li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/@3DPrintingNerd">3D Printing Nerd</a></li> <li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/@TeachingTech">Teaching Tech</a></li> </ul> <p>These are some channels I watch and trust for their content. They have quite a few 3D printing videos, so you should go and watch them for the latest tech in 3D printing.</p> <p>By following these people, you can get the latest updates on software features, new 3D printers, and more.</p> <h3 id="reddit-groups">Reddit groups</h3> <blockquote class="block-tip"> <p>Remember to always read the pin comment or each group before posting</p> </blockquote> <ul> <li><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/3Dprinting/">r/3Dprinting</a></li> </ul> <p>The general Reddit group for 3d printing</p> <ul> <li><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/FixMyPrint/">r/FixMyPrint</a></li> </ul> <p>How can you fix a problem when you don’t know what it’s called? This group will help you with that. Also, see other mistakes that other people have made and suggestions on how to fix them.</p> <ul> <li><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/functionalprint/">r/functionalprint</a></li> </ul> <p>Prints that work don’t need to be complicated; often, they are simple in design. I get inspired by other creations and apply them to my daily life.</p> <ul> <li>r/(your printer name)</li> </ul> <p>If a large enough user base exist, most 3D printers will have a Reddit group dedicated to them. You can go into details on upgrade paths if you are the hands-on type. If your printer is not very popular, you can try its brand name instead, and normally you should be able to find it.</p> <p>I will add stuff to this webpage when I find more interesting stuff.</p> <p>Found something that I missed and should add?  You can contact me at elroytanyuanxiang@gmail.com</p> <p>Last Update 31 March 2024</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="3D-printing"/><category term="Summary"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Resources I use for 3D printing]]></summary></entry></feed>